# Arijit De

TCS-RSP Research Scholar +91 8981800329 arijitde2050@gmail.com Jadavpur University, Kolkata, India An aspiring research scientist looking to explore and contribute in solving real world computer vision problems. An ardent researcher with 4 years of experience in machine learning, data science and artificial intelligence. Also a passionate techie, keen on application software development with experience in developing tools in python, pyQT and QT C++. I Love to collaborate with fellow researchers. Having a good track record of planning, designing and executing a task with excellent sense of time management.



#### **Skills:**

- Programming Python, Java, C++
- Machine Learning PyTorch, PyTorch Geometric, Tensorflow, Scikit-Learn, Medical Open Network for AI (MONAI)
- Medical Imaging SimpleITK, Freesurfer (FSL)
- Data Science Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn
- Frontend HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Latex
- Version Control Git, GitHub



#### **Education:**

Master of Computer Science &
 Engineering, Aug, 2016 - Jul, 2018
 GPA - 8.83

Jadavpur University, Kolkata

Bachelor of Computer Science &
 Engineering, Aug 2010 - Jul 2014
 GPA - 8.81
 Techno India, Kolkata



# Certifications/Licenses:

- Deep Learning, a 5-course specialization, Deeplearning.ai (Apr, 2019)
- MCPS: Microsoft Certified
   Professional, Microsoft (Jun, 2013)
- Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3
   Specialist, Microsoft (Jun, 2013)



# **Professional Experience:**

# Mercedes Benz Research and Development India Bengaluru, India (Aug., 2018 to Sep., 2019)

#### **Data Quality Analyst**

- Developed tools (in Qt C++) for manual quality control of annotated images needed for Vulnerable Road User (VRU) detection.
- Created python scripts for automatic quality checks of labeled/annotated data which increased annotation throughput by 20%.
- Involved in data cleaning and dataset preprocessing for gesture recognition of VRU.

#### Tata Consultancy Services, Kolkata, India

(Aug 2014 - April 2015)

#### **Assistant System Engineer**

- Provided support for client databases using SAP-CRM.
- Responsibilities included generating daily reports, executing
   Change Requests on the database as needed from clients.



# **Teaching Experience:**

#### Edustation, India (Remote) (De

(Dec, 2022 to present)

 Responsibilities included teaching theoretical & practical concepts of various Machine Learning (ML) algorithms & data pre-processing techniques to build efficient end to end ML applications.

#### Upskillz, India (Remote) (May, 2022 to Oct, 2022)

 Taught theoretical concepts on machine learning and data science along with hands-on practical sessions. Guided two ML projects to make students experience the end to end development and designing of ML models.

#### Teaching Assistant, Jadavpur University,

Kolkata (Sep. 2019 to Present)

- Guided students in C Programming Practical (odd semester) and Data Structures and Algorithms with C (even semester).
- Took lectures on Engineering Mathematics as guest lecturer



# **Awards/Achievements:**

- Awarded certificate for valuable contribution as reviewer in 7th International Conference on Computer Vision & Image Processing (CVIP)
- Awarded Guinness World Record participation certificate for participating and breaking the record for most users taking an online computer programming lesson in 24 Hrs.

https://www.guvi.in/ai-for-india-detail

 Awarded TCS-RSP Fellowship by Tata Consultancy Services (TCS)

2020

- Awarded National Doctoral Fellowship (NDF) by AICTE 2019
- Best Paper Award (3rd Position) in Computational Intelligence, Communications and Business Analytics conference (CICBA)

2018



# Freelance Experience:

Developed a Responsive website for Canadian client Docuplus. Link – http://www.docuplus.ca

Built in PHP with MySQL. Hosted in GoDaddy Server.

Sep, 2015 - Jan, 2016

# Languages:

English, Bengali, Hindi

#### **Reference:**

Dr. Ananda Shankar Chowdhury Professor,

Department of Electronics and Telecommunications Engineering, Jadavpur University, Kolkata, India

as.chowdhury@jadavpuruniversity.in

### Technical Laboratory Assistant, Techno India,

Kolkata

(Feb, 2016 to Jun, 2016)

 Responsibilities included designing coding assignments, checking and reviewing student code and also invigilation.
 Subjects involved were C, C++, Shell scripting and DBMS.



#### **Publications:**

- De A, Mhatre R, Tiwari M, Chowdhury AS. Brain Tumor Classification from Radiology and Histopathology using Deep Features and Graph Convolutional Network. In 2022 26th International Conference on Pattern Recognition (ICPR) 2022 Aug 21 (pp. 4420-4426). IEEE. https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/9956229
- A. De, M. Tiwari, E. Grisan and A. S. Chowdhury, "A Deep Graph Cut Model For 3D Brain Tumor Segmentation," 2022 44th Annual International Conference of the IEEE Engineering in Medicine & Biology Society (EMBC), 2022, pp. 2105-2109, doi: 10.1109/EMBC48229.2022.9871685.
   https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9871685
- De A, Chowdhury AS. DTI based Alzheimer's disease classification with rank modulated fusion of CNNs and random forest. Expert Systems with Applications. 2021 May 1;169:114338.
  - https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S09574 17420310265
- De, A., Das, N., Sarkar, R., Saha, P.K., Basu, S. (2019). Design of Synthetic 3-D Pulmonary Phantoms Using 2-D Graphical User Interface. In: Mandal, J., Mukhopadhyay, S., Dutta, P., Dasgupta, K. (eds) Computational Intelligence, Communications, and Business Analytics. CICBA 2018. Communications in Computer and Information Science, vol 1030. Springer, Singapore. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-13-8578-0\_17